Muhammad Fathir Irhas

Software Engineer Jakarta and Bandung

SUMMARY

Email: fathir.irhas@outlook.com Mobile/Whatsapp: +62-812-2444-1284 Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/mfathirirhas

Software Engineer experienced in backend development using several technologies included Go, Java, Rust, and other tools related. Having experiences working in microservices architecture communicating each other through APIs in form of HTTP/REST, gRPC, GraphQL, and message queue. Handling projects and features development, maintaining, and monitoring. Able to work individually or in team. Focus on correctness of works and optimize for speeds. Adaptable, learnability, and write maintainable codes.

EDUCATION

• Universitas Telkom

Bandung, Indonesia

Sarjana Komputer (Bachelor degree in Computer Science)

2012 - 2016

EXPERIENCE

Lifepal

Jakarta

Backend Engineer

May 2022 - Oct 2022

- Working on telesales team on their telesales app in Rust.
- o **Tech Stacks** Rust, Tokio, Go, KubeMQ, Redis, Postgresql

• Tiket.com Jakarta

Backend Engineer

November 2020 - December 2021

- o Team Flight Prepurchase
- o Tech Stacks Go, Java Spring, MongoDB, Redis, Kafka, RabbitMQ, etc.
- **Project** Creating internal mock server for mocking part of inter-services communications, especially partner and integration with flight supplier.
- Working on flight search caching tools to populate search cache preemptively for promos purpose.

• Tokopedia Jakarta

Software Engineer

July 2018 - April 2020

- **Team** Fintech
- Tech Stacks Golang, Javascript, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, NSQ, gRPC, and GQL.
- o Saldo Tokopedia Handling Saldo Service as journaling every transactions in Tokopedia
 - * Design and implements transactions code for every products and services by storing them in service's local cache refreshed every n minutes using goroutine background process.
 - * Handling Saldo Service internal dashboard.
 - * Migrate old code from Perl related to saldo service into Golang.
 - * Help other teams and services to integrate into Saldo Service.
 - * Saldo buyer and seller separatations, refactoring APIs to adjust saldo separations, along with its grpc and gql apis.
 - * Saldo buyer and seller separatations, revamping saldo's monolith service along with its front end in Golang template with javascript(jquery) frontend
 - * Refactor codes for unit tests coverage, adding testability to the code.
 - * Data query for specific data fetching and changes not covered by service's api and internal dashboard.
- Internal Dashboard Work on internal dashboard as backoffice to business and ops teams.
- **EGold** Create datadog monitoring dashboard for Tokopedia Emas buy and sell success, attempts rate and collect error reporting in the dashboard.
- Monitoring Monitor services running through server's logs, grafana and datadog dashboard.
- Support Support other teams to integrate. Support ops teams relating issues from customers.

• Anabatic

Serpong, Tangerang
Nov 2016 - Jun 2018

Software Engineer/Technical Consultant

• Tech Stacks Java(Spring), PHP(Codeigniter), MySQL, Javascript.

May 11, 2023

- Emporia Digital Raya Subsidiary of Anabatic. Worked on Eksporaja, a product as a channel partner with Alibaba for exporter in Indonesia. Maintain Emporia main website. Worked on Udaily another product from emporia for apartment cluster management and daily stuffs.
- Anabatic Worked on client site. Supporting development in Allianz.

SKILLS

- Backend Development using Golang, Rust and few Java
- Databases with Postgresql, Mysql, SQLite, and Mongodb
- In-memory cache with Redis
- API with HTTP, gRPC, GraphQL, Message Queue.
- Some design patterns required in software developments.
- Maintaining and Debugging.
- Unit Testing and Integration Testing.
- Benchmarking and Monitoring.
- ...and others related.

LINKS

- $\bullet \quad \textbf{Github} \ \text{https://github.com/mfathirirhas} \\$
- Rust Note notes I take while learning Rust https://mfathirirhas.github.io/rust-note
- ... more on my github